Jacob Williams

Currently located: Birmingham, UK

Mobile: 07979768424

E-mail: jjwill@hotmail.co.uk

PROFILE

BSc Computer Science graduate, who achieved a 1st. Through my degree and work experience I have been determined to constantly improve my analytical skills, so I can understand how to do things better in a different situation. I am dedicated to producing work which I am proud of and do not let pressure get to me, especially when I am driven by working on projects that I have a deep interest in.

KEY SKILLS

- Technical Ability: Experienced with Python, HTML, Java, C#, Lisp, PHP and T-SQL.
- Adaptable: Independently learns new skills and programming languages quickly.
- Time management: Well organised and punctual.
- **Computational Thinking:** Can logically break down and compute problems.
- Communication: Can comfortably interact with people appropriately and professionally.
- Industry Knowledge: Experience with stand-up meetings and agile / scrum.

EDUCATION

09/2017 – 06/2021 **Aston University**

Studying: Computer Science BSc Grade: 1st - 76%

Modules include: Internet Applications and Techniques 84%

Computer Graphics 82%

Data Structures and Algorithms with Java 74%

09/2015 – 06/2017 *Alderbrook Sixth Form*

Subjects Studied & Maths – B Physics – D

Grades (A-Level): Computer Science – B Biology (AS Level) – D

09/2010 – 06/2015 *Alderbrook School*

10 A* - C including: Computer Science - **A** English Language - **B**

Maths – A* Core / Additional / Further Science – A/A/B

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

07/2014 (work experience, aged 15) Esendex

- Learned multiple aspects of web design.
- Observed skills needed for this role.
 - How agile / scrum processes work in a business environment.
- Helped redesign and create a new website for the company.
 - Used HTML, JavaScript and CSS.

07/2016 (work experience, aged 17) Warwick Analytics

- Worked in a small team.
- Helped create a new concept for the company's software.
- Provided example pages of the concept.
 - o Used HTML, JavaScript and JavaScript Libraries.
 - Used Git to share and store the project.

10/2015 - 04/2019

Becketts Farm Shop

- Worked in a team to meet deadlines.
- Communicated with customers to give good quality service.
- Learned how to use new software quickly.
- Trained a younger member of the team and gave them the skillset required for the job.

06/2019 – 06/2020 (placement year) Rimilia

- Worked in a team to help set up customers and solve ongoing customer issues.
- Worked with T-SQL and C# in a business environment.
- Created a C# framework for processing a specific file type.
- Learned the database structure and financial knowledge required quickly.
- Used version control in a business environment.

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- I am a member of the Aston Computer Science Society.
- Strong passion for computer games.
- I am a fan on Formula 1 racing.
- Enjoy casual programming in my spare time.
- Interested in new and leading technology such as IoT, artificial intelligence, electric / driverless cars to name a few.

REFERENCES

Academic Referee:

Dr Michal Konečný (Personal Tutor)

Lecturer in Computer Science

<u>m.konecny@aston.ac.uk</u>

Aston University,

Aston Street,

Birmingham,

B4 7ET